<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Blog|Hara</title>
        <link>www.hara.cf/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog|Hara</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 13:28:27 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="www.hara.cf/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>On Hope</title>
            <link>www.hara.cf/posts/hope/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 13:28:27 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>www.hara.cf/posts/hope/</guid>
            <description>Of all the vile and pitiful tools in the disservice of humanity, hope takes the charge. While all of life is merely an attempt to budget breaths drawn, hope, in it’s melancholic glory convinces simple men to spend themselves in futility.
What else convinces a lone warrior to swing his sword one more time, to spend the last of his sinking breaths on an attempt so futile perhaps the gods laugh thunderously at the mere sight of it,what else whispers connivingly in the ears of a broke single-mother to sell her body to salivating dogs in mere hope of food on the table every night, what else persuades mortal men to take that chance, one more time?</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Of all the vile and pitiful tools in the disservice of humanity, hope takes the charge. While all of life is merely an attempt to budget breaths drawn, hope, in it’s melancholic glory convinces simple men to spend themselves in futility.</p>
<p>What else convinces a lone warrior to swing his sword one more time, to spend the last of his sinking breaths on an attempt so futile perhaps the gods laugh thunderously at the mere sight of it,what else whispers connivingly in the ears of a broke single-mother to sell her body to salivating dogs in mere hope of food on the table every night, what else persuades mortal men to take that chance, one more time?</p>
<p>Hope, of course. While you unknowingly spend your leftover days, is it not hope that makes you feel something better ‘can’ happen?</p>
<p>We have the vile spirit of hope battling every ounce of joy in pursuit of ‘better’ while many amongst us advocate it as a byproduct of visuals. Visuals of men who got lucky, convincingly ignoring the uncountable souls spent in the same pursuit. We are blinded by hope, intoxicated by it.
It’s all a gamble!</p>
<p>I am reminded of a game of Russian Roulette, as mentioned by Nassim Taleb in his book, “Imagine an eccentric tycoon offering you $ 10 million to play Russian roulette, i.e., to put a revolver containing one bullet in the six available chambers to your head and pull the trigger. Each realization would count as one history, for a total of six possible histories of equal probabilities. Five out of these six histories would lead to enrichment; one would lead to a statistic, that is, an obituary with an embarrassing cause of death. The problem is that only one of the histories is observed in reality; and the winner of $ 10 million would elicit the admiration and praise of some fatuous journalist. Like almost every executive I have encountered during an eighteen-year career on Wall Street, the public observes the external signs of wealth without even having a glimpse at the source (we call such source the generator.) Consider the possibility that the Russian roulette winner would be used as a role model by his family, friends, and neighbors.</p>
<p>While the remaining five histories are not observable, the wise and thoughtful person could easily make a guess as to their attributes. It requires some thoughtfulness and personal courage. In addition, in time, if the roulette-betting fool keeps playing the game, the bad histories will tend to catch up with him. Thus, if a twenty-five-year-old played Russian roulette, say, once a year, there would be a very slim possibility of his surviving until his fiftieth birthday — but, if there are enough players, say thousands of twenty-five-year-old players, we can expect to see a handful of (extremely rich) survivors (and a very large cemetery).”</p>
<p>All of this happens perhaps because we are too afraid to face the nature and consequences of our decision making or perhaps because it’s not you that’s pulling the trigger, it’s hope.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
